Deepa Chauhan

Operations Team Leader 20deepa.chauhan@gmail.com 7217853525

About Me

Self-motivated, organized and result oriented hard-working professional possess 10+ years experience with customer service industry. Exposure to various communication channels like chat, email and voice. Experienced in managing, coaching and motivating team to achieve desired targets. Ready to accept new challenges and become important part of organization's growth and success.

Work Experience

Telus International- Operations Team Leader -May 2021-July 2023

Lead and manage a team of CCR (Customer Care Representative) in the optimal execution of Call Center operations activities (i.e., taking calls, addressing customer-Technicians issues / complaints.

Ensure that each team member meets / exceed their goals and metricson a daily, weekly, and monthly basis. Monitoring contacts handled by team and provide required feedback and coaching for better customer satisfactionscore. Appreciate good performers and motivate team. Analyzes and determines what affects agent / team performance, establishes solutions.

Manage escalations calls live and scheduled calls as subject matter expert. Follow up with the open issues and call back scheduled by self for further investigations.

Manage the queue and controls abandoned calls by utilizing available eximet and resources.

Teleperformance- Assistant Manager Customer Care (TL)-Aug 2019 – April 2021

Create an inspiring team environment with an open communication culture. Set clear team goals. Manage day-to-day planning, ensuring that the teams consistently deliver on speed and accuracy within the agreed SLA frameworks and achieving desired customer satisfaction score.

Managing escalations calls and follow up for open issues, taking live escalation calls. Lead, develop and coach Executives. Participate in calls with the client to understand expectations, provide feedback and reports and resolve queries or escalations. Coordinate with the Training, QA and L&D team to conduct needs analyses and facilitate/impart skills trainings for the team.

Report on team performance, customer feedback and daily activities. Monitor and manage leaves, attendance, breaks, attrition, etc. for the team. Co-ordinate with internal support functions to help resolve issues for the team.

Webhelp India Pvt. Ltd - Sr. Associate and web content moderator- Sept 2017 - Aug 2019

Assisting potential customers with quires related to various products and services and converting leads into sales. Handling post sales issues and billing complaints for Europe's leading direct-to-consumer media and Entertainment Company.

Web content review, hold, delete and decide which content should go live as per standards and guidelines for world's first short video-sharing social networking service.

John Keells BPO – Sr. Associate - Feb 2014 - Sept 2017

Resolving customer quires and complaints about billing, plan, promotions, benefits and services. Resolving issue and providing resolution for level two escalations for biggest wireline and wireless telecommunication company of US.

Assisting potential customers on chat and converting leads into sales forbiggest phone, internet and TV service provider of Canada.

Convergys India Pvt. Ltd – Customer Care Executive Mar 2012- Aug 2013

Resolving customer quires and complaints about billing, plan, promotions, benefits and services. Escalating complaints to relevant department following specified procedure and documentation for telecom giant of US.

Education and Skills

- Fine Arts Diploma from Kalaneri Art Gallery & Academy of Fine Arts.
- BBA (Diploma Graduate) from NIM University through Distant Learning, 2009.
- H.S.C from Ajmer board Rajasthan with 66%, 2002.
- S.S.C from Ajmer board Rajasthan with 79.38%, 2004.
- Proficient and moderate computer user, MS Office (Word, Excel and PowerPoint)

Personal Information

Father's name: Mr. Mahendra Singh Chauhan

Marital Status: Married

Date of birth : 20th Sept, 1987

Declaration

I do hereby declare that the information provided above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Noida

(Deepa Chauhan)